Guide to the Larry McMurtry Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Other Projects
  - Projects Considered
    - Leaving Cheyenne, Essays on American Rodeo: Outline; Background material (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - The Life and Adventures of Nat Love; Typed letter Martin Starger to McMurtry; Photocopy of novel, July 14, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Pepper Hill TV series by Jerome and Bridget Dobson: Typescript; Note by McMurtry (Box 25, Folder 19)
      Photocopied typescript draft; Manuscript note
    - Pepper Hill TV series by Jerome and Bridget Dobson (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Revivalist project (?): New York magazine, May 22, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - The Sawdust Trail by Langley Hall (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - The Sawdust Trail by Langley Hall (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - The Sawdust Trail by Langley Hall (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - The Abernathy Boys: Summary (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - The Abernathy Boys: Background material (notes and photographs) (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - The Abernathy Boys: Correspondence, John Van Eyssen to McMurtry, includes photocopy of typed letter Fred Miller to John Van Eyssen and The Glory Road excerpt (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - The Abernathy Boys: Background material (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - The Abernathy Boys: Background material; Catch 'Em Alive Jack by John R. Abernathy (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Bareback Rider by Robert Godfrey and Victress Hitchcock: Treatment; Typed letter Robert Godfrey to McMurtry, October 16, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - A Few Days on Weasel Creek by Joanna Brent: Notes (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - A Few Days on Weasel Creek by Joanna Brent (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - A Few Days on Weasel Creek by Joanna Brent (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Camp Community, edited by Jessie A. Garrett and Ronald C. Larson (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Heart Mountain by Douglas W. Nelson. Background material (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Heart Mountain by Douglas W. Nelson (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Heart of the County by Bland Simpson; Typed letter Mike Wise to McMurtry; Typed letter Joe Naar to Mike Wise; Draft, May 1983 (Box 25, Folder 37)
      TLS; Photocopied typescript draft
    - The Washington Project (George Stevens): Note, George Stevens to McMurtry; Typescript notes (Box 25, Folder 38)
- Works by Other Authors
  - Old Jack by Wendell Berry (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Typescript; Envelope
  - Chapter XLIV from Xerxes by Louis Couperus (translation) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - The Life and Times of Miles Blackwell by Monty Diamond (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - To a Novelist Dying Young by Ronnie Dugger in the Washington Post, June 18, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - The Frontier Myth and Southwestern Literature by Larry Goodwyn in American Libraries, April 1971 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Music for a Broken Piano by James Baker Hall (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Photocopied page proofs
  - Unidentified page 103 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Clem Maverick by R.G. Vliet (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Translation of The Croton by Jos Vandeloo: Written in Bluebooks (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Translation of The Croton by Jos Vandeloo (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Translation of The Joke by Jos Vandeloo (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Translation of The Joke by Jos Vandeloo (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Translation of The House of Strangers by Jos Vandeloo: Chap. 1 & 2 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Translation of The House of Strangers by Jos Vandeloo: Chap. 3 & 4 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Translation of A Little Man from Poland by Jos Vandeloo (Box 26, Folder 15)
    Manuscript; Typescript
  - Translation of The Enemy by Jos Vandeloo (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Country of the Heart by Barbara Wersba (Box 26, Folder 17)
    Photocopied book
- Photographs
  - Photos of McMurtry (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Photos of McMurtry (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Photos of McMurty (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Photos of McMurty (Box 26, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous
  - Interviews, Articles and Reviews
    - Hud and Horseman Pass By: News articles, reviews and ads (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Horseman Pass By and Leaving Cheyenne: Review excerpts in memo form (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Typed letter E. Pauline Degenfelder to McMurtry and typescript of McMurtry and the Movies: Hud and The Last Picture Show (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Typed letter Elizabeth Wachendorfer to George Christian; Audiotape of McMurtry interview by George Christian (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Come to McMurtry Country in Tempo Sunday Magazine, July 6, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Coming of age in Texas: The Novels of Larry McMurtry by Charles Peavy in Western Am. Lit., Fall 1969 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - A Larry McMurtry Bibliography by Charles D. Peavy, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Collage interview and interview notes (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Article on McMurtry in Texas Observer, Vol. LXVIII, No. 1, January 16, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      Publication
    - News articles about McMurtry (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Publicity
    - Terms of Endearment: Ads (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Last Picture Show (movie): Advertising Aids (Box 27, Item 4)
    - HUD: Movie stills (Box 27, Item 5)
    - Lonesome Dove (novel): Poster (Box 27, Item 6)
  - Book Catalogs
    - Booked Up: Permanent Want List (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Booked Up: Catalogue 1, Fall 1971; Ms note (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Booked Up: Spring 1977 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - The Bookman: A Miscellany Catalogue 2 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - The Bookman: Catalogue 3, Modern First Editions (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - The Bookman: Catalogue 4, Belles-Lettres (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - The Bookman: Catalogue 5, Continental Literature in Translation (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - The Bookman: Catalogue 7, Modern First Editions (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - The Bookman: Catalogue 10, 1929 (2 copies) (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - The Bookman: Catalogue 11, Literary Periodicals (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - The Bookman: Catalogue 16, Literary Periodicals: A-M (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - The Bookman, Christmas Catalogue (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - The Brick Row Book Shop, Catalogue 84, Am. Lit., 1875-1917 (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - Wm: Reese Co: Catalogue 7, Literature (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - Wm: Reese Co: Catalogue 11, Literature (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - Other
    - Stationary, Larry McMurtry and W.J. McMurtry (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - Larry McMurtry signature; Store notice written by L.M.; Unidentified illustration; Unidentified note (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - Larry McMurtry. A Collection of Manuscript Material, for sale by Michael Kunkel (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - Loose file dividers, with notes (Box 26, Folder 51)
    - Twayne's United States Authors Series: Larry McMurtry by Charles D. Peavy (Box 27, Item 1)
      Photocopied publication in 3-ring binder